Oleksii Avramenko

About

10 years of software engineering experience, a dozen of programming languages and quite a few technology stacks. Passionate about functional programming, Scala, Haskell, category theory, logic and everything in between. Spend most of my free time learning Mandarin and Spanish, hacking on things or just being outside more. I've been traveling full time and working remotely since March 2018, most likely I'm somewhere in Southeast Asia right now.

Contacts

• email: alexey.awramenko@gmail.com

twitter: twitter.com/vvviiimmm

• medium: medium.com/@olxc

• website: vvviiimmm.github.io

Work experience

Team/Tech Leader at Sisense Inc.

December 2016 - Present

As a "Data Connectors" team we're working on providing connectivity to different data sources, normalizing the schema and extracting data for analytical purposes; targeting a wide range of data sources, like relational databases (MSSQL, MySQL, Postgres, etc), file based (CSV, Excel files), analytical databases and warehouses (Redshift, Google BigQuery, Snowflake), web services and social networks (Facebook, Twitter, Stripe, Hubspot, etc) and many more. We're using Scala for all of our projects with a high emphasis on functional programming. Doing my best to mentor newcomers and educate other people about the benefits of FP.

PL: Mostly Scala, a bit of Java and C#, targeting Windows and Linux with Kubernetes orchestration.

Scala Developer at Sisense Inc.

December 2015 - December 2016

Started as a team of 2 people our goal was to design and implement an infrastructure for connecting to various data sources and bring data into our own data warehouse. The new framework design had to support multiple run time environment and we end up having implementation on JVM using Scala (the one I was leading) and .NET using C#. I was also focused on developing easy to use and well documented SDK for connectors development for the Sisense community.

PL: Scala and C#

Senior C++ Developer at Teramind Inc.

August 2015 - November 2015

Startup company specializing in website and application monitoring, file tracking, network capture, session recording and activity analysis. I was leading OS X development branch of the project making sure that all features are aligned across platforms with the same quality level. Designed and implemented kernel extensions for darwin kernel that had to:

- Control filesystem authentication: monitor or block folder activity, external drives mounting, network shares connections, cloud drives uploads/downloads
- Filter network tcp/udp packets. Receive, decode and parse application layer protocols like http, smtp, pop3, tls/ssl etc and eventually make a decision based on packet's content.

PL: C++ for application code and C for kernel extensions, targeting OS X

C++ Developer at Playtech, Poker

July 2014 - August 2015

Playtech's Poker department develops online poker platform. I was responsible for unifying multiple (platform dependent) code bases under one solution that would simplify app's development, deployment and maintenance. That involved porting existing functionality from iOS to Windows and Mac and vise versa. There were a lot of technical challenges that required deep knowledge in various low level components and compilers.

PL: Mostly C++

C++/C# Developer at Playtech, Videobet

September 2013 - July 2014

Videobet works on gaming terminals platform and casino management system. I was mainly focused on tooling, testing automation and infrastructure. Worked on a set of tools which, hosted on physical terminal, allow remote and automated comprehensive testing of all platform's functionality.

PL: C++ and C# targeting Windows Embedded

Lead Programmer (C++/Lua) at ERS Game Studios

January 2011 - September 2013

Game development company. Participated in development of more than 20 shipped games, including three of them as a lead programmer. Had chance to do all kinds of work — developing engine internals, mentoring junior developers, drawing art, creating animations and sounds.

PL: Lua, C++ and Python

July 2010 - December 2010

Game development company. Worked mainly on a game engine and a level editor.

PL: C++ and Python

Education

Kyiv National University of Technologies and Design

Computer Science, 2008 - 2012

References

Available upon request